cro.ie 2013-09-23

# CRO Privacy Security Statement

## (A) Privacy

Personal data supplied to CRO via this website pursuant to the Companies Acts 1963-2012 (for instance, notification of appointment of a company officer, change of company officer’s particulars) or the Registration of Business Names Act 1963 (for instance, registration of a business name by an individual, firm or body corporate, or change of address of the owner of a registered business name) does not come within the Data Protection Acts 1988-2003, being "personal data consisting of information that the person keeping the data is required by law to make available to the public". Such data therefore falls outside the terms of this Privacy Statement. This means that the conditions and information set out below do not apply to any personal data supplied to CRO on this website by any person pursuant to the Companies Acts 1963-2012 and/or Registration of Business Names Act 1963.

 **Identity**

This website is www.cro.ie. If you wish to discuss any matters relating to the processing of personal data on the CRO's website, please contact us at [crowebmaster@djei.ie](mailto:crowebmaster@djei.ie) or by post at CRO, Parnell House, 14 Parnell Square, Dublin 1, marked for the attention of Aoife King.

 **Purpose**

The purposes for which personal data supplied by you on our website will be used will be:

(a) in respect of payment for services supplied to you by CRO - either to debit the account maintained by you with CRO with the search fees/transaction fees incurred by you during your use of this website, or to debit your credit/laser card if you opt to use same to pay for those services while using this website. CRO policy is to retain the minimum amount of information necessary to be able to deal with any subsequent queries regarding the transaction. In connection with payment by laser/credit card, we retain the customer e-mail address and IP address only. The documents requested are supplied to this address. We do not retain any laser/credit card details. Such details are retained on our behalf by Realex (see under Disclosure, below) and may be reviewed by CRO through a web link. In relation to services paid for by debiting of customer accounts, the customer’s email address is retained.

The IP address is an address from which you access our website (an IP address is the number automatically assigned to your computer when you are surfing the web. IP addresses are used to analyse trends, administer the site, track users' movements, and gather statistical information and are not linked to personally identifiable information).

(b) to register you as a subscriber to our email newsletter service. For this purpose, only your email address has to be supplied to us, and this is retained by CRO in order that the newsletter may be transmitted to you. If you at any time cancel your subscription to the email newsletter, your email address will be retained by us for record purposes concerning your subscription to the newsletter service but will be used by CRO for no other purpose.

(c) To register you for our online e-filing service. The personal information collected is user name, address, email, PPSN, phone number, fax number, and DX number and exchange, and details of the user’s administrator, if relevant. These details are retained indefinitely, and are used by CRO to identify the registered user whenever he/she logs on to our online e-filing service and for populating the presenter detail field on any e-filed forms being submitted by such user.

 **Disclosure**

Personal data supplied will not be released to any third parties, save that credit card information will be securely transferred to Realex, a secure online payments provider.

 **Right of Access**

A person has the right of access to the personal data held by CRO as a result of what has been supplied by him/her on this website. The access request should be in writing and accompanied by a fee of €6.35 per request. A reply will be furnished to you within 40 calendar days. Written requests to the above postal address accompanied by payment of the fee and a copy of your photo ID, duly certified, signed and dated by a Garda, Doctor, Solicitor, Priest, Peace Commissioner or Commissioner for Oaths will be accepted by CRO in this regard.

 **Right of Rectification**

If the personal data supplied by you to this website in the context of payment for services supplied, or registration for the CRO email newsletter service or online filing service is inaccurate, you have the right to have said personal data corrected. There is no charge for complying with such a request and we will comply with your request within 40 days. Please forward a written request for rectification to CRO, Parnell House, 14 Parnell Square, Dublin 1, marked for the attention of Aoife King.

 **Cookies**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage.

Google may transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purpose set out above.

## (B) Security

CRO takes its security responsibilities seriously, employing the most appropriate physical and technical measures, including staff training and awareness, and these measures are reviewed regularly.

To ensure the security of your credit card information when you use same to discharge CRO fees on this site, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. You will see the padlock in your browser’s security display indicating that the transfer of all data between your browser and our site has been encrypted.

When you supply us with your laser/credit card information in the context of an online transaction for services supplied to you, this information is not retained on this site. Rather, it is securely transferred to Realex, a secure online payments provider. All CRO retains is your email address.

* * *

Print this page
